{"Topic": "Space", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which of the following phenomena cannot be observed on the surface of the Moon?", "op1": "Rising and setting of the Sun", "op2": "Solar eclipse", "op3": "Motion of comets", "op4": "Twinkling of stars", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following planets has a revolution time which is shorter than its rotation time?", "op1": "Jupiter", "op2": "Venus", "op3": "Mars", "op4": "Uranus", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which planet looks reddish in the night sky?", "op1": "Jupiter", "op2": "Saturn", "op3": "Mars", "op4": "Mercury", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which female astronaut spent the maximum time in space?", "op1": "Lisa Norwak", "op2": "Kalpana Chawla", "op3": "Sunita Williams", "op4": "None of these", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which planet has the fastest revolution time?", "op1": "Mercury", "op2": "Uranus", "op3": "Neptune", "op4": "Jupiter", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "An astronaut in outer space will observe sky as", "op1": "White", "op2": "Black", "op3": "Blue", "op4": "Red", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following planets rotates in a direction opposite to the direction of earth's rotation?", "op1": "Mars", "op2": "Jupiter", "op3": "Venus", "op4": "Mercury", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the average distance (approximate) between the Sun and the Earth?", "op1": "70  x  105 km", "op2": "100  x  105 km", "op3": "110  x  106 km", "op4": "150  x  106 km", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "NASA's Deep Impact space mission was employed to take detailed pictures of which comet nucleus?", "op1": "Halley's Comet", "op2": "Hale-Bopp", "op3": "Hyakutake", "op4": "Tempel 1", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following planets has a lesser rotation time than the Earth?", "op1": "Jupiter", "op2": "Mars", "op3": "Mercury", "op4": "Venus", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the name of the first woman space tourist?", "op1": "Jullian Moore", "op2": "Anousheh Ansari", "op3": "Paula Radcliffe", "op4": "Namira Salim", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Storms of gases are visible in the chromospheres of the Sun during", "op1": "Cyclones", "op2": "Anticyclones", "op3": "Lunar eclipse", "op4": "Solar eclipse", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The name of the world's first black spaceman is", "op1": "Prensa Latina.", "op2": "Arnaldo Tamayo Mendez.", "op3": "Yury Rumanenko.", "op4": "Robert Mendereze.", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The first person to enter into space was", "op1": "Valentina Tereshkova", "op2": "Edward H. White", "op3": "Yuri Gagarin", "op4": "Alan Shepard", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "How much time does light require to travel distance of 150,000,000 kilometers from the Sun to the earth?", "op1": "8 1/3 minutes", "op2": "8 1/2 minutes", "op3": "8 1/4 minutes", "op4": "9 minutes", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The name of the galaxy in which the earth is a planet is", "op1": "Andromeda", "op2": "Ursa Major", "op3": "Ursa Minor", "op4": "Milky Way", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The asteroid belt is located between which two planets in the solar system?", "op1": "Earth and Mars", "op2": "Mars and Jupiter", "op3": "Jupiter and Saturn", "op4": "Saturn and Uranus", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The planet that lies at the outermost orbit of the solar system is :", "op1": "Saturn", "op2": "Neptune", "op3": "Mercury", "op4": "Uranus", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The planet nearest to the sun is :", "op1": "Saturn", "op2": "Jupiter", "op3": "Mars", "op4": "Mercury", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "A star of which colour can be said to be the coolest?", "op1": "Yellow", "op2": "Blue", "op3": "Red", "op4": "Black", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In order to know the time, the astronauts orbiting in an earth satellite should use :", "op1": "a watch having mainspring to keep it going", "op2": "a pendulum clock", "op3": "either a pendulum clock or a watch", "op4": "an alarm clock", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The planets on either side of the earth are :", "op1": "Mercury and Venus", "op2": "Mars and Jupiter", "op3": "Mars and Venus", "op4": "Venus and Saturn", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following Planets have no moons?", "op1": "Pluto and Mercury", "op2": "Mars and Venus", "op3": "Mercury and Venus", "op4": "Pluto and Mars", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Black hole is :", "op1": "A dark hollow cavity", "op2": "A massive collapsing star", "op3": "The other side on the moon", "op4": "The other side of sun", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "How old is the solar system (approximately)?", "op1": "5 billion years", "op2": "50 billion years", "op3": "500 billion years", "op4": "5 million years", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following planets/celestial bodies is nearest to the Sun?", "op1": "Saturn", "op2": "Uranus", "op3": "Neptune", "op4": "Pluto", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "According to International Astronomical Union which one of the following has lost its status as a planet?", "op1": "Jupiter", "op2": "Uranus", "op3": "Neptune", "op4": "Pluto", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "\u2018New Horizons\u2019 spacecraft was launched by NASA to study which of the following planet?", "op1": "Mars", "op2": "Pluto", "op3": "Jupiter", "op4": "Mercury", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The coldest planet in the solar system is :", "op1": "Pluto", "op2": "Venus", "op3": "Uranus", "op4": "Jupiter", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the nearest galaxy to the Milky Way?", "op1": "Andromeda", "op2": "Cartwheel galaxy", "op3": "Pinwheel galaxy", "op4": "Whirlpool galazy", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which planet has the solar system's highest mountain Olympus Mons?", "op1": "Jupiter", "op2": "Uranus", "op3": "Venus", "op4": "Mars", "Answer": 3}]}